# JARED MURPHY

## **DATA SCIENTIST**

☑ jared.m.murphy@protonmail.com (904) 502-0547 10910 Queens Blvd Apt 7J, Forest Hills, NY 11375

## **SUMMARY**

I am a Data Scientist with a background in Mathematics and Statistics. I currently specialize in Time Series Analysis, and for my most recently completed project I used ARIMA modeling to test the validity of Covid-19 mortality data released by Johns Hopkins University and the CDC. I am currently in the final stages of completing a comprehensive technical analysis of the crypto-asset Bitcoin. In this project I compare the behavior of Bitcoins price action to that of several other asset classes and provide means for making long term forecasts for the future price of Bitcoin.

## **EDUCATION**

University of North Florida June 2013 - Aug. 2015

**B.S. Statistics 2015** 

Springboard Data Science Career Track

Intensive courrse in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL

Mar. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Oct. 2016 - Current

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Self-Employed, Carpenter/Residential Painter, Hudson Valley, NY

Finish carpentry, rough carpentry, drywall, concrete, residential painting

High School Equivalency Instructor, Dutchess Community College, Poughkeepsie, NY Mar. 2016 - Oct. 2016

Teaching high school math and science to students of all ages

Sales Associate, DSW, Jacksonville, FL Aug. 2010 - Aug. 2015

Customer service, shipping and receiving

## SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Python, pandas, numpy, statsmodels, sklearn

MACHINE LEARNING: SUPERVISED LEARNING: KNN, Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, SVM, Precision, Recall, Accuracy, F1, ROC

MACHINE LEARNING: UNSUPERVISED LEARNING: K-means Clustering, Hierarchical Clustering, Mean-Shift Clustering, PCA, Cosine Similarity

MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS: Calculus I, II, III, Linear Algebra, Mathematical Statistics, Probability , Bayesian Methods, Hypothesis Testing, ANOVA

RELATIONAL DATABASES: SQL, MySQL, SQLite

DATA VISUALIZATION WITH PYTHON: matplotlib, seaborn

## **PROJECTS**

Excess Deaths Due to Covid-19 May 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Python Tools: numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, statsmodels
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Used CDC mortality data with ARIMA modeling and Facebook's Prophet to estimate excess deaths in US for 02/01/2020-10/31/2020-10/2$
- Excess deaths were then compared to reported deaths due to Covid-19 and no significant discrepancies were found
- https://github.com/jared-m-murphy/Springboard/blob/main/Capstone\_1/Capstone\_Final.ipynb

### Bitcoin: A Technical Analysis

- Python Tools: numpy, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn
- Provided a description of Bitcoin as an emerging asset class and a comprehensive overview of its historical price action
- Retrieved various asset price data from API's using pandas
- Created customized charts using matplotlib to provide visual comparisons of Bitcoins volatility and returns to those of other asset classes
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Developed complex functions in python to extract meaningful insights from time series financial data}$
- Investigated Bitcoins popular Stock to Flow model and provided price predictions for the coming year
- $\bullet\ https://github.com/jared-m-murphy/Springboard/blob/main/Capstone\_2/Bitcoin.ipynb$

## **AWARDS**

Graduated Summa Cum Laude, University of North Florida Aug. 2015

Inducted into Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honors Society, Florida Eta Chapter

#### Aug. 2015

## **VOLUNTEERING**

Kunzang Palchen Ling (Buddhist Center), Carpenter/General Contractor

Red Hook, NY

Construction and maintenance of a Buddhist monastery in upstate New York

Jan. 2016 - Sept. 2019

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021